<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="2.4.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-11-24T10:12:59-05:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Franco Alvarado</title><subtitle>Welcome to my website.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Your Dream Cakes</title><link href="/projects/YourDreamCakes" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Dream Cakes" /><published>2016-11-22T13:24:17-04:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T13:24:17-04:00</updated><id>/projects/YourDreamCakes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/YourDreamCakes">&lt;p&gt;Your Dream Cakes is a custom dessert and catering service in South Florida. I built and designed the website using WordPress. I also designed the logo and business cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;yourdreamcakes-site&quot; alt=&quot;Website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;yourdreamcakes-cards&quot; alt=&quot;Business cards&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[yourdreamcakes-cards]: 
[yourdreamcakes-site]:&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Your Dream Cakes is a custom dessert and catering service in South Florida. I built and designed the website using WordPress. I also designed the logo and business cards.

[yourdreamcakes-cards]:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Strangelet Website</title><link href="/projects/StrangeletBooks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strangelet Website" /><published>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</updated><id>/projects/StrangeletWebsite</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/StrangeletBooks">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strangelet&lt;/em&gt; was a bimonthly literary magazine of fantasy, science fiction, and magical realism. In addition to creating and co-managing the website, I was also one of its co-founders and managed the &lt;a href=&quot;../StrangeletPress&quot;&gt;production of the books and ebooks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[]:
[]:
[]:
[]:&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Strangelet was a bimonthly literary magazine of fantasy, science fiction, and magical realism. In addition to creating and co-managing the website, I was also one of its co-founders and managed the production of the books and ebooks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Strangelet Press</title><link href="/projects/StrangeletBooks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Strangelet Press" /><published>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</updated><id>/projects/StrangeletPress</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/StrangeletBooks">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Strangelet&lt;/em&gt; was a bimonthly literary magazine of fantasy, science fiction, and magical realism. In addition to managing the design and production, I was also a co-founder, the &lt;a href=&quot;../StrangeletWebsite&quot;&gt;website designer&lt;/a&gt;, and art editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;em&gt;Strangelet&lt;/em&gt;, I typeset the book in Caslon with the display text as Marta. The title page typeface is Hightower and the cover a combination of typefaces to reflect the tone of the books: strange, bizarre, eerie. We produced bimonthly issues, very short, around 50 to 70 pages each, and combined them in an omnibus at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;strangelet-covers&quot; alt=&quot;Our covers&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;strangelet-spread&quot; alt=&quot;A sample spread&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;strangelet-poem&quot; alt=&quot;A poem&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;strangelet-story-open&quot; alt=&quot;Story opener&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;strangelet-titlepage&quot; alt=&quot;Title page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the ebook edition, I was able to pull colors from the covers as the link and highlight color. By setting up the InDesign files myself, we were able to have a streamlined and efficient production process for ebook production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;strangelet-library&quot; alt=&quot;All of the Strangelet issues&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;strangelet-story-open-ebook&quot; alt=&quot;Story opener, ebook&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[strangelet-covers]: 
[strangelet-spread]: 
[strangelet-titlepage]: 
[strangelet-library]: 
[strangelet-poem]: 
[strangelet-story-open]:
[strangelet-story-open-ebook]:&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Strangelet was a bimonthly literary magazine of fantasy, science fiction, and magical realism. In addition to managing the design and production, I was also a co-founder, the website designer, and art editor.

[strangelet-covers]: 
[strangelet-spread]: 
[strangelet-titlepage]: 
[strangelet-library]: 
[strangelet-poem]:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rice and Rocks</title><link href="/projects/RiceAndRocks" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rice and Rocks" /><published>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</updated><id>/projects/RiceAndRocks</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/RiceAndRocks">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rice and Rocks&lt;/em&gt; is a children’s book published by Wise Ink. I was contracted to create three different fixed-layout versions, one enhanced version with music and two more versions without the music enhancement, in EPUB3 and KF8/Mobi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;riceandrocks&quot; alt=&quot;Opening spread of Rice and Rocks&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;riceandrocks-inlibrary&quot; alt=&quot;Rice and Rocks in the iBooks library&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Rice and Rocks is a children’s book published by Wise Ink. I was contracted to create three different fixed-layout versions, one enhanced version with music and two more versions without the music enhancement, in EPUB3 and KF8/Mobi.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Once Magazine</title><link href="/projects/Once" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Once Magazine" /><published>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</updated><id>/projects/OnceMagazine</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/Once"></content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Litweaver</title><link href="/projects/Litweaver" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Litweaver" /><published>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</updated><id>/projects/Litweaver</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/Litweaver">&lt;p&gt;Litweaver was a library of original young adult literature developed for schools and distributed as EPUB and Mobi/KF8 files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;litweaver-library&quot; alt=&quot;Selection of the Litweaver ebook library&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I worked with Litweaver for two years, creating over 100 ebooks for the series, which included short stories, novels, poems, and plays. I also developed a paragraph-numbering system for them. Previously they had been using non-semantic tables, which presented various problems in resizing and accessibility. Due to compensate for e-reading technology, instead of using for a purely CSS3 solution, I included the numbering in the mark-up and used CSS to position the paragraphs appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;p-numbers&quot; alt=&quot;Paragraph numbers in a Litweaver title&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Litweaver was a library of original young adult literature developed for schools and distributed as EPUB and Mobi/KF8 files.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Crimson Romance</title><link href="/projects/CrimsonRomance" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Crimson Romance" /><published>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</updated><id>/projects/CrimsonRomance</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/CrimsonRomance">&lt;p&gt;Crimson Romance is the romance line at Adams Media. This is an ebook-first series. For this series, I helped with a transition to a CMS-based workflow. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;crimsonlibrary&quot; alt=&quot;Library of Crimson Romance ebooks&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to the quick turnaround with this series, I was presented with an interesting challenge. The CMS filled in the metadata fields for the EPUB export; however, since the content was outpacing the metadata for this fast-paced workflow, I had to enter in that information manually: the cover, author name, title, and ISBN. Initially, I set up a set of regexes that I would run upon opening the files, but eventually I created a Python script. The script is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/francofaa/RomanceEPUBCleanup&quot;&gt;here on github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">Crimson Romance is the romance line at Adams Media. This is an ebook-first series. For this series, I helped with a transition to a CMS-based workflow.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Beowulf</title><link href="/projects/Beowulf" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beowulf" /><published>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</published><updated>2016-11-22T12:24:17-05:00</updated><id>/projects/Beowulf</id><content type="html" xml:base="/projects/Beowulf">&lt;p&gt;For this edition of &lt;em&gt;Beowulf&lt;/em&gt;, as translated by J. Lesslie Hall, I had to tackle a layout with three different types of marginalia: line numbers, asides, and footnotes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;beo-ded&quot; alt=&quot;Dedication&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;beo-fm&quot; alt=&quot;Front matter opener&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;beo-marginalia&quot; alt=&quot;Spread with all marginalia&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;beo-marginalia-dt&quot; alt=&quot;Marginalia detail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;beo-chap-open&quot; alt=&quot;Chapter opener spread&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the cover, I created a Viking ship on the water, all created with typographical ornaments. These were then echoed in the title page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&quot; alt=&quot;Title page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[]:
[]:
[]:
[]:
[]:
[]:
[]:&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="projects" /><summary type="html">For this edition of Beowulf, as translated by J. Lesslie Hall, I had to tackle a layout with three different types of marginalia: line numbers, asides, and footnotes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Death of Gueda Hesme</title><link href="/blog/2016/10/28/Death-of-Gueda-Hesme/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Death of Gueda Hesme" /><published>2016-10-28T14:04:17-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-28T14:04:17-04:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/10/28/Death-of-Gueda-Hesme</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/10/28/Death-of-Gueda-Hesme/">&lt;p&gt;Tia Gueda Hesme lived in the house, having worked for the Von Kromer family for as long as anyone could remember. No one knew how she was related to the family, and Calébres and Alessandro doubted she was ever young. Her eyes were white and murky, and she looked as old as a tree, gnarled and knotted with wrinkles. She never moved as she sat in her chair, aside from moving her hand to her mouth to take a puff from her cigar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—-Right down there, in the plaza, she told the boys in her strange accent, there used to be a well, and one of the boys—his name was Raul, one of the sons of Marcos. Marcos, now, he should be your great-great-great uncle. But yes, his boy would go to that well every day to get water, early in the morning, and one day, a voice called from inside the well, crying out to him, Up there, if you help me, I’ll give you all the money you could ever hope for. Just look, the voice said, and Raul saw something flash, like silver catching the sun. So Raul lowered the bucket and said, Get in the bucket, but the voice said back: No, you have to come down yourself and get me. So your cousin went down into the well, with the rope tied around his waist, and they never saw him again, no. Whatever was down there, snatched him away, and as she said this, her hand snatched something invisible out of the air. Alessandro flinched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She would tell the boys a story every day, about heroes and princesses, about wars and adventures, all of them stories she had heard throughout her life in Egypt and Europe and India and South America and the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–This is a story my grandmother told me. It takes place a very long time ago, when this town was still jungle and when God still spoke to the best of us directly, when this was a wicked city where people only cared about themselves and they would eat each other. There was one good man that lived there, named Lucio, and two angels came to visit him to tell him to leave because God was going to destroy the city with fire from the sky. The angels told him to leave and not look back—-it was God’s command. So Lucio packed everything up and took his daughters and his wife away. They climbed the mountains, and as they crossed the bridge that took them out of sight of the city, Lucio’s wife paused in the middle and turned around and looked back and sighed. And for that, she was turned into a pillar of salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—But why? Alessandro asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaned forward toward the shape of the boy and strained her voice:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—Because she disobeyed God. There is something beautiful about disobeying, boys. To turn and sigh. It is so human, and I always loved her for that. I never even knew her name, and I have forgotten the rest of the story. Perhaps Lucio and his daughters were more favorable in the eyes of God, but in my cloudy eyes, it is she I love and remember, as a fellow soul, who has never disobeyed herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaned back in her chair and sat in silence for several minutes, cuing to the boys that they should leave. She began ending stories like that more often in the months before her death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—The dead could come back, she told them one afternoon. Strong as oxen, with the same brains as well. In the Caribbean, strange things like that happen. They eat chickens alive and chant and go into frenzies, and those men who come out of the ground would work in the fields like slaves. Landowners would just steal people out of the ground. But that’s a foul thing to do to a man, boys, to use his body like that. It is disrespectful. Promise me you’ll never do such a thing, boys. Yes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—Yes, Tia Hesme, they replied, but the comment seemed so strange to them, so frightening, they didn’t know what to think of it, so they would leave the room whenever she would say things like that, making up some excuse and occupying their minds on something else—for, had it been someone else, one of their school friends or family members, and not this ancient woman, heavy with sincerity and simplicity, it might have not been so frightening. There was too much truth in the spaces between her words. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as she neared her death, in the last weeks, those moments happened more often, where she would ramble and say something so disturbing that the boys had to leave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—A cigar, please, Alessandro, she said to the shape sitting in front of her, and the shape came closer to her and handed her one. A low flick sound, followed by the orange that burned on the end of the cigar. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—When you get to be my age, she told them, things become whole again, combining in colors and shapes. I believe it is like this when you are an infant, and you are first born and you flail around and weep uncontrollably, inconsolably. With eyes glazed over with your tears and your mother’s blood. But now, even though I see like that again, I have learned, in all my many, many years of things parting, how to cope with it. I can see clearer than ever before, and I can see things for what they really are: shapes and colors, and we all blend into each other. That’s what’s important to remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She stopped speaking and looked forward, the cigar still burning in her mouth. She crossed her legs, placing her right leg on her left knee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—Tia Hesme? said Alessandro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But no reply, and as he said it, the cigar fell out of her mouth and into her lap. The two boys stood and stared at the fabric burn, afraid to touch the cigar or approach the woman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—Tia Hesme? Alessandro said louder. They refused to touch the woman at all, and Alessandro ran out of the room, calling for his mother. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calébres stayed and looked at Gueda Hesme’s eyes. Some say she spoke to him before she died, but all Calébres told the family when they came into the room, was that she asked him to put the cigar out, and he did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—Is she OK? Alessandro asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their father stepped forward and touched her wrist, finding no pulse. Had the boys’ father not declared it, no one would have thought she was dead.  &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Franco A. Alvarado</name><email>franco.faa@gmail.com</email></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Tia Gueda Hesme lived in the house, having worked for the Von Kromer family for as long as anyone could remember. No one knew how she was related to the family, and Calébres and Alessandro doubted she was ever young. Her eyes were white and murky, and she looked as old as a tree, gnarled and knotted with wrinkles. She never moved as she sat in her chair, aside from moving her hand to her mouth to take a puff from her cigar.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This is the title</title><link href="/blog/2016/10/24/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is the title" /><published>2016-10-24T14:04:17-04:00</published><updated>2016-10-24T14:04:17-04:00</updated><id>/blog/2016/10/24/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2016/10/24/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;Tom&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &amp;#39;Hi, Tom&amp;#39; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Andy Dost</name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>
